Newland/Zeuner Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
Guides to Special Collections in the Music Division of the Library of Congress
Newland/Zeuner Collectioncirca 1735-circa 1900
ML31.N48
Newland, William Augustine, 1813-1901
circa 2,000 items 57 boxes 20 linear feet
Music Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Primarily music (printed and ms.) for piano, 2 or 4 hands, and songs, with a concentration in sacred vocal works in Latin and English. (The music in Latin may represent the only known source of pre-Cäcilienverein 19th-century American Catholic Church music.) Composers range from Mozart and Rossini to George F. Root and Oliver Shaw. The collection contains the largest extant source of music by Charles Zeuner which was purchased by Newland after Zeuner's death.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791.; Newland, William Augustine, 1813-1901.; Newland, William Augustine, 1813-1901.; Root, George F. (George Frederick), 1820-1895.; Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868.; Shaw, Oliver, 1779-1848.; Zeuner, Charles, 1795-1857. Newland/Zeuner collection. circa 1735-circa 1900.; Zeuner, Charles, 1795-1857. Selections.
Organizations
Catholic Church--United States--Hymns.
Subjects
Music--United States--19th century.; Sacred vocal music.
Administrative Information
Provenance
Purchased in 1929.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Access and Restrictions
The Newland/Zeuner Collection is open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Performing Arts Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use. Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Note
Organist, composer and writer Edward Hodges, grandfather of George, was born in Bristol, England in 1796 and acquired a MusD from Cambridge in 1825. After a very brief tenure as organist at St. James's Cathedral in Toronto, Hodges accepted in 1839 a similar position at Trinity Church in New York City.
Scope and Content Note
The Newland/Zeuner Collection constitutes the working library of professional musician William A. Newland, who was active in many different musical circles in 19th-century Philadelphia. It consists almost exclusively of music, in both manuscript and printed form, and reflects the diversity of sacred and secular musical activity in America in the late-18th and early-19th century.
The imprints in the collection, both European and American, consist primarily of music for piano (2 or 4 hands) and songs. Manuscripts in the collection include both instrumental and vocal works of many genres, with a particular concentration in sacred vocal works in both Latin and English. The music in Latin is especially noteworthy in that it may represent the only known source of pre-Cäeciliaverein 19th-century American Catholic church music. Newland's many transcriptions and arrangements illustrate the common practice of setting operatic and other secular melodies to sacred texts for church use; the collection abounds in settings for liturgical anthems and hymns such as "Ave Maria," "O Salutaris Hostia" and "Regina Coeli." Similarly, the 2 and 4 hand piano transcriptions in the collection demonstrate 19th-century America's fondness for piano arrangements of operatic and orchestral works.
The composers represented in this collection constitute a representative sampling of the mix of European and American music prevalent in the United States in the mid-19th century, ranging from Mozart and Rossini to George F. Root and Oliver Shaw. American composers are particularly well-represented in the collection by popular 19th-century instrumental forms such as the quickstep, quadrille, gallop, rondo polacca, march, and waltz, which are found in both the keyboard works and those scored for band or small orchestra.
Of primary significance in the Newland/Zeuner collection is the existence of the largest extant source of the music of Charles Zeuner, a student of Johann Nepomuk Hummel and tenth president of the Handel and Haydn Society of Boston. Arriving in Boston from his native Germany in the 1820's, Zeuner became well-known as an organist and composer of singular skill. Newland acquired Zeuner's library after the latter's tragic death by suicide in 1857. Of particular note among the manuscript scores of vocal, instrumental, and orchestral works are the holograph scores of his works for organ.
Zeuner's numerous manuscripts of German songs are complemented by his variations on American standards such as "Yankee Doodle," "Hail Columbia," and "Home Sweet Home." Quicksteps named for President Tyler and Governor Everett of Massachusetts, a Funeral March for President Harrison, and pieces designated specifically for the Fourth of July illustrate that both Newland and Zeuner are representative of the many 19th-century emigré composers who were fully integrated into the mainstream of American music.
The Newland/Zeuner Collection was processed in November 1991 by Timothy Bullard, Claudia Widgery, and Robert Saladini.
Organization of the Newland/Zeuner Collection
The Newland/Zeuner Collection is organized in 6 series:
Writings of William A. Newland
Collections of Instrumental and Vocal Music
Instrumental Music
Vocal Music
Instruction and Study Materials
Music of Charles Zeuner
http://lccn.loc.gov/96704662
Container List
- Writings of William A. Newland (Box 1)
  Holograph writings, bound and unbound.
  Arranged by title.
  - Advice to Organists, Photocopy of original housed in the Reuss Collection, Archdiocese of Philadelphia, Archives and Historical Collections (Box 1)
  - [Unidentified], Notes on the personnel and activities of Holy Trinity Church in Philadelphia (Box 1)
- Collections of Instrumental and Vocal Music (Box 1-5)
  Holograph and printed scores, bound and unbound.
  Arranged by genre and composer or title.
  - Printed music (Box 1-4)
    - Clementi, Muzio
      - Oeuvres Complettes de Muzio Clementi. Cahier I, VI. Leipsic: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d. (Box 1)
    - Haydn, Franz Joseph
      - Oeuvres Complette de Joseph Haydn. Cahier I-IV. Leipsic: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Pl. no. 1428, 2204. (Box 1-2)
    - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus
      - Oeuvres Complettes de Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart. Cahier III, IV, VII-XI, XIII, XIV, & XVII Leipsic: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d. (Box 2-3)
      - Sarah Regina Newland, Music book, hard cover; printed piano music for 2 and 4 hands by various composers; handwritten index on inside front pages (Box 4)
  - Manuscripts (Box 4-5)
    - Litanies Hymns Vespers Chant Mass., On t.p.: W. A. Newland, Organist; hard cover, oblong, with index on inside and outside of back cover (Box 4)
    - Mass. Kyrie and Gloria. Dies irae. Dona eis. Requiem see also: for organ/vocal score by W. A. Newland, Box 30, scored for orchestra and voices; Title on spine; [on first page] Messa Cantata con piena Orchestra, Fatta in Venezia.; oblong; soft cover, brown ink (Box 4)
    - Overtures. Piano solo. Violin., operatic overtures transcribed for solo violin and solo piano; oblong, soft cover (Box 4)
    - [Unidentified], On cover: William A. Newland / Port Royal av. / 21st ward / Phila; empty hard cover with listing of 64 works on inside verso (Box 5)
    - [Collection of piano music (2 and 4 hands) with 6 pages of printed songs] (Box 5)
    - [Collection of piano music for 2 and 4 hands, preceded by an aria by Dittersdorf], (German text) (Box 5)
    - [Collection of short pieces for piano and songs with German text; oblong] (Box 5)
    - [Collection of music for piano (4 hands), violin, and oboe with piano] (Box 5)
    - [Music book, signed on inside front page by Mrs. Eliza Cockey], songs and piano pieces; hard cover (Box 5)
- Instrumental Music (Box 5-23, Box 56-57)
  - Music for solo instruments (Box 5-20, Box 57)
    - Organ - Printed music (Box 5)
      - Rinck, Johann Christian Heinrich
        - Nos. 7-10, Rink's Op. 2, 8 (Box 5)
      - Batiste, Edouard
        - The Great Organ: a selection of pieces performed at the Inauguration [Nov. 2, 1863] of the Great Organ (Boston Music Hall) and at subsequent concerts Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co., n.d., title page only (Box 5)
    - Organ - Manuscripts (Box 5-6)
      - By Composer (Box 5-6)
        - Albrechtsberger, Johann Georg
          - Organ Fugue (Box 5)
        - Handel, George Frideric
          - Messiah, excerpts (Box 5)
          - Sechs Fugen (Box 5)
        - Haydn, Franz Joseph
          - Adagio für die Orgel (Box 5)
        - Newland, William Augustine (arranger)
          - [Unidentified], arrangements for the organ (Box 5)
          - Capriccio for organ (Box 5)
        - Pleyel, Ignaz
          - Quintetto 1 (Box 6)
        - Rembt, John Ernst
          - Six trios, 1787, dedicated to Carl Philipp Emanuel Bach (Box 6)
        - Russell
          - A Celebrated Introduction and Fugue (Box 6)
        - Umbrecht, Carl Gottleib
          - 51 Orgelstücke (Box 6)
        - Wagner, C.
          - Die Jungfrau von Orleans (Box 6)
        - Wills, J.
          - Voluntary (Box 6)
      - Title only (Box 6)
        - Grand Capriccios for Organ (Box 6)
        - [Compilation of fugues by various composers; hard cover] (Box 6)
        - [Miscellaneous organ works] (Box 6)
    - Piano, 2 hands - Printed music (Box 7-9)
      - By Composer (Box 7-9)
        - Adam, Adolphe and Ludwig Wenzel Lachnith
          - Premières Leçons et 38 Pièces agréables Handstücke de tout genre par gradation, le tout doigté, pour le Pianoforte à l'usage des Élèves du Conservatoire de Musique, par Adam & Lachnith Leipzig: C. F. Peters, n.d., Pl. no. 887. (Box 7)
        - Beethoven, Ludwig van
          - LIme [51st] Sonate pour le Pianoforte composée par Louis van Beethoven. Op. 54 Vienne: Bureau des arts et d'industrie, [1806]., Pl. no. 507. (Box 7)
          - Rondo pour le Clavecin ou Piano Forte par Louis van Beethoven. [Op. 51] Vienne: Artaria, [1802]., Pl. no. 884. (Box 7)
          - Sieben Ländlerische Tänze für's Piano-Forte von L. v. Beethoven Berlin: F. S. Lischke, [1799]., Pl. no. 1551. (Box 7)
        - Clementi, Muzio
          - Deux Sonates pour le Forte Piano composées par Muzio Clementi. Oeuvre 34. Nouvelle Editione, et corrigées par l'auteur Vienne: Artaria et Comp., [1795?]., Pl. no. 557. (Box 7)
          - Tre Sonate Per Clavicembalo o Forte-Piano Composte dal Sig. Muzio Clementi. Opera [23] Vienna: T. Mollo Compl., n.d., Pl. no. M.1164. (Box 7)
        - Cramer, J. B. (Johann Baptist)
          - Collection des Sonates brillantes pour le Piano Forte. Nro. [1] Composées par J.B. Cramer. Munic: M. Falter, [1800]. (Box 7)
          - Three Sonatas for the Piano-Forte by J. B. Cramer. Op. 23 London: R. Birchall, n.d. (Box 7)
        - Czerny, Carl
          - Quatrième Rondino pour le Pianoforte seul sur un motif favori de Mr. Fesca composé par Charles Czerny. Op. 39 Vienne: A. Diabelli et Comp., [18-]., Pl. C. et D. No. 1252. (Box 7)
        - Diabelli, Anton
          - Euterpe, eine Reihe moderner und vorzüglich beliebter Tonstücke zur Erheiterung in Stunden der Musse für das Piano-Forte herausgegeben von Anton Diabelli. No. 220. No. [55,93,95] [Vienna]: A. Diabelli et Comp., n.d., Includes: No. 55 - Bollero von Caraffa (Ognor più tenero) (Ja meine Liebe soll) gesungen von Mad: Metzer = Vespermann. Pl. C. et D. No. 797. No. 93 - Duetto (All Idea di quel metallo) (Strahlt auf mich der Blitz des Goldes) aus der Oper: Der Barbier von Sevilla, v. Rossini. Pl. C.et D. No. 1315. No. 95 - Duetto (Pace e gioja) (Glück und Huld mein Herr) aus der Oper: Der Barbier von Sevilla, von Rossini. Pl. C. et D. No. 1317. (Box 7)
        - Dussek, Johann Ladislaus
          - Thême Varié Pour Le Forte-Piano compossé por J. L. Dussek Vienne: Artaria et Comp., [1807?]., Pl. no. 1837. (Box 7)
        - Field, John
          - Rondeau Favori pour Piano-Forté composé par John Field. No. 2. Offenbach s/M: J. André, [182-]., Pl. no. 4488. (Box 7)
        - Freystädtler, Franz Jacob
          - 10 Variazionen über das alte wohlbekante Preussische Lied: Schwerin bist wirklich todt? für das Pianoforte von Freystädtler Leipzig: C. F. Peters, n.d., Pl. no. 1062. (Box 7)
        - Gelinek, Joseph
          - Rondeau ou Polonoise favorite pour le Piano Forté, par Gelinek. Offenbach s/M: J. André, n.d., Pl. no. 3664. (Box 7)
          - Sonatina leicht und angenehm für das Piano-Forte von Herrn Abbé Gelinek. No. [2] Wien: Artaria Comp., [1803?]., Pl. no. 1637.; 2 copies (Box 7)
          - Variationen über die Cavatine in Rossini's Tancred, für das Pianoforte von Abbé Gelinek. No. 96 Braunschweig: Musikalischen Magazine aus der Höhe, n.d., Pl. no. 1589. (Box 7)
          - Variations pour le Pianoforte composées par L'Abbé Gelinek. No. [8,93,100] Cologne: N. Simrock, n.d., Also published in Bonn; Includes: No. 8 - 8 Variations Sur le Trio: Copia Si Tenera, de l'Opera: Palmira. Pl. no. 1422. No. 93 - 8 Variationen über den beliebten Fransens=Brunn Walzer. Pl. no. 1415. No. 100 - Tema de l'Opera: Jean de Paris. Pl. no. 1916. (Box 7)
        - Glück, Carl
          - Twenne Walsar och en Cotillon componerade och arrangerade för Piano-Forte af Carl Glück Stockholm: Ebeling, n.d. (Box 7)
        - Hässler, Johann Wilhelm
          - Caprice et Sonate pour le Clavecin ou Pianoforte par Jean Guillaume Haesler. Oeuv. V St. Petersbourg: J. D. Gerstenberg et Comp., [17-]., Pl. no. 40. (Box 7)
          - Fantaisie et Sonate pour le Clavecin ou Forte-Piano par Jean Guillaume Haessler. Oeuvre III St. Petersbourg: Gerstenberg et Comp., [17-]., Pl. no. 23. (Box 7)
          - Fantaisie et Sonate pour le Clavecin ou Forte-Piano par Jean Guillaume Haessler. Oeuvre IIII St. Petersbourg: Gerstenberg et Comp., [17-]., Pl. no. 27. (Box 7)
          - Prelude et Sonate pour le Clavecin ou Forte Piano par J. G. Haesler. Oeuvre VI Moscou: Johann Wilhelm Hässler, [17-]., Pl. no. 13. (Box 7)
        - Häuser, Johann Ernst
          - Terpsichore oder Museum der neuesten Modetänze. Eine musicalische Zeitschrift für mittlere Pianofortespieler, herausgegeben von J. E. Häuser. Zweiter Jahrgang in 6 Heften Meissen: F. W. Goedsche, n.d., fragment (Box 7)
        - Herz, Henri
          - Grande Fantaisie Brillante pour le Piano, sur un motif favori de l'Opéra d'Ambroise Thomas: La Double Échelle, par Henri Herz. Op. 98 Mayence: B. Schott, [18-]., Pl. no. 4956. (Box 7)
        - Hummel, Johann Nepomuk
          - La bella Capricciosa pour le Pianoforte composée par J. N. Hummel Leipsic: Breitkopf & Härtel, [1817]., Pl. no. 3055. (Box 8)
          - Grande Sonate pour Pianoforte par J. N. Hummel. Op. 20 Vienne: J. Riedl, [1816?]., Pl. no. 528. (Box 8)
          - Neue Wiener Walzer für's Forte-Piano in Musik Gesetzt von J. N. Hummel Hamburg: Joh. Aug. Böhme, n.d., Pl. no. H.7. (Box 8)
          - Rondeau pour le Piano Forté par Jean Nep. Hummel de Vienne Offenbach s/M: Jean André, n.d., Pl. no. 2195. (Box 8)
          - Souvenirs de Paganini Fantaisie pour le Piano-Forte par J. N. Hummel Paris: A. Farrenc, n.d., Pl. no. A.F.467. (Box 8)
          - Trois Airs Anglais Variés pour le Piano-Forte par J. N. Hummel. Oeuvre 120. No.1 - The Ploughboy Paris: A. Farrenc, n.d., Pl. no. A.F.474. (Box 8)
        - Kirmair, Frederick Joseph
          - Deux Airs Favoris, variés pour Piano-Forté par Kirmair. No. 100 du journal de musique pour les Dames. Seconde édition Offenbach s/M: Jean André, [1805?]., Pl. no. 1858. (Box 8)
        - Kleeberg, Christian Theophilus
          - Vermischte Tänze für das Clavier oder Forte-Piano componirt von Kleeberg. Erste Sammlung Braunschweig: Musikalischen Magazine auf der Höhe, n.d., Pl. no. 183. (Box 8)
        - Kuhlau, Friedrich
          - Sonatinas, Op. 55 [S.l.]: André, n.d., Pl. no. 13174; no. 3 incomplete, 4-6 only (Box 8)
        - Lumbye, Hans Christian
          - Eine Sommernacht in Dänemark, Pl. no. 7271. (Box 8)
        - Martin y Soler, Vicente
          - [L'Arbore de Diana], Pl. no. 156. (Box 8)
        - Moscheles, Ignaz
          - Grandes Variations sur la Marche favorite de L'Empereur Alexander I pour le Piano-Forte composées par Ig. Moscheles. Oeuvre 32 Mayence: B. Schott, [18-]. (Box 8)
        - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus
          - Quodlibet pour le Forte-Piano tiré des Oeuvres par W. A. Mozart. Nor. 1 Vienne: Artaria & Comp., [1806]., Pl. no. 1811 (Box 8)
          - [Sonata Collection], Incomplete, first 6 pages missing (Box 8)
          - [Waltz], fragment (Box 8)
        - Müller, August Eberhard
          - Trois Sonatines progressives pour le Piano-Forte par A. E. Müller. Oeuvre XVIII Vienne: Hoffmeister & Comp, [1798]. (Box 8)
        - Ostade, Adrian von
          - Walse aus Adrian von Ostade pour le Piano Forte Mayence: B. Schott, n.d., Pl. no. 412. (Box 8)
        - Päer, Ferdinando
          - Variations Pour le Piano-Forte Sur une Polonaise de l'Opera: La Griselda, de F. Paër Paris: A. Farrenc, n.d., Pl. no. (7). (Box 8)
        - Pfeiffer, Theodor
          - Melodieenbuch Lfg. II. No. 12 - Kathinka-Polka, von Pfeiffer. [and] No. 13 - Das Herzeleid: (Wie i bin verwichen, zu meim Dienderl g'schlichen.) Philada.: G. André, n.d., Pl. no. 6894.; Pubisher information stamped (Box 8)
        - Ries, Ferdinand
          - Air favori de la Petite Russie varié pour le Piano-Forté, par F. Ries. Oeuvre 56 Offenbach s/M: Jean André, [182-]., Pl. no. 4570 (Box 8)
          - Divertissement pour le Piano-Forté avec accompagnement d'une Flûte, composé par Ferd. Ries. Oeuvre 62 Offenbach s/M: Jean André, n.d., Pl. no. 4742 (Box 8)
          - Douze Bagatelles pour le Piano forte Composeés par Ferd. Ries. Oeuvre 58, Liv. I & II Bonn: N. Simrock, [1816]., Pl. no. 1203 (Box 8)
          - Fantaisie en forme de rondeau pour le Piano-Forté, sur une Pièce de Mozart, de son Opéra: l'Enlèvement du Sérail par Ferd. Ries Offenbach s/M: Jean André, [182-]., Pl. no. 4796. (Box 8)
          - 8me Fantaisie pour le Piano-Forté, sur des thêmes favoris de l'opéra: Zelmira de Rossini composée par F. Ries. Oeurvre 121 Offenbach s/M: Jean André, [1823]., Pl. no. 4801. (Box 8)
          - Marche de l'opéra: Tancredi de Rossini variée pour Piano-Forté, par Ferd. Ries. Oeuvre 96. No. 25. des Var. Offenbach s/M: Jean André, [182-]., Pl. no. 4904. (Box 9)
          - Rondeau pour le Piano-Forté composé par Ferd. Ries. Oeuvre 106. No. 3 Offenbach s/M: Jean André, [182-]., Pl. no. 4901. (Box 9)
          - Rondeau Brillant pour le Piano-Forté, composé sur un thême du H. R. Bishop par Ferd. Ries. Oeuvre 104. No. 3 Offenbach s/M: Jean André, [182-]., Pl. no. 4905. (Box 9)
          - Rondo per il Pianoforte sopra la Cavatina: (Di piacer mi balza il cor) nell opera: La Gazza ladra, di Rossini, composto da Ferd. Ries. Op. 89 Vienna: Cappi e Diabelli, [182-]., Pl. C. et D. No. 1440. (Box 9)
          - Rondo pour le Pianoforte sur la Cavatine de Rossini "Una voce poco fa" ("Frag ich mein beklomen Herz") de l'Opera: le Barbier de Sevilla composé par Ferdin. Ries Brounsvic: Magazin de Musique, n.d., Pl. no. 1467. (Box 9)
          - Six Exercices pour le Piano-Forté Composés par F. Ries. Oeuvre 31 Bonn: N. Simrock, [18-]., Pl. no. 931. (Box 9)
          - Trois Airs favoris Variés pour le Piano-Forté, par F. Ries. Oeuvre 82. No. 2 - La Barcarole Vénitienne Offenbach s/M: Jean André, [182-]., Pl. no. 4541. (Box 9)
          - Variations sur un célèbre Air Ecossais pour le Pianoforte par Ferd. Ries. Oeuvre 101. No. 1. No. 29 des Variations Leipsic: Breitkopf & Härtel, [182-]., Pl. no. 3792. (Box 9)
        - Schmitt, Aloys
          - Etudes pour le Piano forte par Aloïse Schmitt. Op. 16. Prémière Partie contenant des exercices préparatoires servant à acquérir une indépendance et égalité des doigts possibles, suivies de vingt Etudes Bonn: N. Simrock, [18-]., Pl. no. 1618.; Schmitt signature on cover (Box 9)
        - Schmitt, Jacques
          - Marsch fürs Clavier, von J. Schmitt, Pl. no. 20. (Box 9)
        - Steibelt, Daniel
          - Rondeau Piémontais, pour Piano-Forté, Composé par D. Steibelt. Offenbach s/M: J. André, n.d., Pl. no. 4595. (Box 9)
        - Strauss, Johann
          - Les Fantastiques (Die Fantasten.) Nouvelle suite de valses [by] Strauss. Op. 139. [Paris]: Schlesinger, n.d., Pl. no. M.S. 5764.; also: Gabrielen-Valse de Jean Strauss. (Box 9)
        - Thalberg, Sigismond
          - Cinq Fantaisies pour le Piano sur des motifs des Opéras de Mozart, Meyerbeer & Bellini composées par Sig. Thalberg. Op. 10. No. 3 - Capuletti Paris: Maurice Schlesinger, [18-]., Pl. no. M.S.1972. (Box 9)
        - Wohlfahrt, Robert
          - Sieges-Jubel. Marsch. Op. 49, Pl. no. M.F.-J.1.; [also] Wanderlied by Friedr. Baumfelder. (Box 9)
      - Title only (Box 9)
        - No me mires asi! Habanera para piano por E. Z. Buenos Ayres: Emilio Cornu, n.d., Publisher information stamped (Box 9)
        - Musikalische Unterhaltungen. Erstes Quartal, von Neujahr bis Ostern 1775. [No. 18] Leipzig: Adam Friedrich Böhme, n.d. (Box 9)
        - My Aine Kind Dearie, a favorite Scotish Air, arranged with Variations for the Piano Forte. London: Preston, n.d. (Box 9)
        - XXIV Pièces pour le Piano-Forté à l'usage des Commencans. Oeuv: 1 Maience: B. Schott, [18-]., Pl. no. 531. (Box 9)
        - [Miscellaneous piano fragments] (Box 9)
    - Piano - Manuscripts (Box 10)
      - By Composer (Box 10)
        - Beethoven, Ludwig van
          - [Unidentified], Miscellaneous works for piano (Box 10)
        - Phillips, H.
          - The Emigrant Ship see: Wade, I've Wandered in Dreams, Box 10
        - Thalberg, Sigismond
          - Home! Sweet Home! op. 72 (Box 10)
        - Wade, J. Augustine
          - I've Wandered in Dreams, also includes: The Emigrant Ship by H. Phillips (Box 10)
      - Title only (Box 10)
        - The Blessings of Peace, theme and variations [by William A. Newland?] (Box 10)
        - Fantaisie and Nocturne (Box 10)
        - Overture aus der ?? Eigesinnige (Box 10)
        - Sammlung Neuer Tänze (Box 10)
        - [Compilation of piano pieces] (Box 10)
        - [Fugues] (Box 10)
        - [Gallops] (Box 10)
        - [Marches] (Box 10)
        - [Mazurkas] (Box 10)
        - [Polkas] (Box 10)
        - [Quadrilles] (Box 10)
        - [Rondos] (Box 10)
        - [Schottisches] (Box 10)
        - [Sonatas] (Box 10)
        - [Variations] (Box 10)
        - [Waltzes] (Box 10)
        - [Miscellaneous piano works] (Box 10)
        - [Miscellaneous piano fragments] (Box 10)
    - Piano, 2 hands: Transcriptions - Printed music (Box 11-12)
      - By Composer (Box 11-12)
        - Auber, Daniel-François-Esprit
          - Ouverturen für das Piano-forte solo. Nro. 2. Gustav, oder der Maskenball v. D. F. E. Auber. Wolfenbüttel: Druck und Verlag von L. Holle, n.d., Pl. no. (470). (Box 11)
          - La Neige. Opera en quatre actes composé par D. F. E. Auber arrangé avec accompagnement de Piano-Forté No. 103. Francfort: A. Fischer, n.d., Overture only (Box 11)
        - Beethoven, Ludwig van
          - Ouverturen für das Piano-Forte solo. [Nro. 4,5,6] Wolfenbüttel: Druck und Verlag von L. Holle, n.d., Includes: Nro. 4 - Fidelio. Pl. no. (472). Nro. 5 - Egmont. Pl. no. (473). Nro. 6 - Coriolan. Pl. no. (474). (Box 11)
          - Symphonien für das Pianoforte zu zwei Händen, arrangirt von Louis Winkler. Braunschweig: Henry Litolff's Verlag, n.d., Pl. no. 1513, 1527, 1537, 1544, 1553, 1554, 1547, 1550, 1585. (Box 11)
          - Triumph-Marsch aus dem Trauerspiele Tarpeia von Louis von Beethoven. Berlin: F. S. Lischke, n.d., Pl. no. 1006. (Box 11)
        - Bellini, Vincenzo